<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career Development on Brian Z</title>
    <link>http://blog.brianz.bz/tags/career-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career Development on Brian Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 18:41:18 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.brianz.bz/tags/career-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On technical blogging</title>
      <link>http://blog.brianz.bz/post/on-technical-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 18:41:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.brianz.bz/post/on-technical-blogging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.brianz.bz/post/getting-started-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;inaugural post&lt;/a&gt;, I had been wanting to start a technical blog for some time.
Mainly a a way of capturing things I learn or discover so that it can benefit others. As an
engineer I consume a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of content on the web. Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, when we hit some technical hurdle
or are trying to figure something out that we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before, our job become that of an
internet sleuth, combing the web for answers on StackOverflow, blogs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By nature I&amp;rsquo;m not much of a self promoter and in some ways, I&amp;rsquo;ve tended to view blogs and &amp;ldquo;personal
brands&amp;rdquo; as shameless self-promotion (nothing personal &lt;a href=&#34;http://simpleprogrammer.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Sonmez&lt;/a&gt; or
other bloggers).
One day I listened to &lt;a href=&#34;http://simpleprogrammer.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.se-radio.net/2015/12/se-radio-episode-245-john-sonmez-on-marketing-yourself-and-managing-your-career/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Software Engineering
Radio Podcast&lt;/a&gt;
where his topic was that of soft skills. I&amp;rsquo;m old enough to realize that the smartest engineers
are not necessarily the most successful. Being a good engineer is &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; important&amp;hellip;but it&amp;rsquo;s
good to have some personal skills rather than being the Doritos-eating-mt-dew-drinking person who
lives in a hovel and cranks out code. The soft skills are the ones which can really propel your
career and work forward taking it from great or good to amazing. Soft skills were the topic of
discussion in this podcast interview with John and it really resonated with me&amp;hellip;with that I got
over my unfair view of being a self-promoter and whipped this up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped in head first and signed up for John&amp;rsquo;s 7-part course on boosting your career. Now, I
can&amp;rsquo;t say one way or another how or &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; this will help your career trajectory, but it&amp;rsquo;s really
helped to motivate me to get this blog up and running and to attempt to be a bit more visible in
the &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; eye. I highly recommend it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://devcareerboost.com/blog-course/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://devcareerboost.com/blog-course/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a real example, I authored and open sourced the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/clearcare/servant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;servant
library&lt;/a&gt; over a year ago. We&amp;rsquo;ve been running in production at
work for &lt;em&gt;over a year&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been publicized outside of my small team. Just blogging
about it and creating some links could help somewhere out there who&amp;rsquo;s interested in authoring a
microservice with Python. And, even if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen, it&amp;rsquo;s been fun to talk about what I work
on and show something that I&amp;rsquo;m proud of, even if the audience is small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John&amp;rsquo;s email campaign is pretty light and gives you some practical assignments to get your blog up and
running. I can definitely say that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be writing this now had I not enrolled&amp;hellip;so with
that, I tip my hat to &lt;a href=&#34;http://simpleprogrammer.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt; and say thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/l2JJHgjz1uaEncXew/giphy.gif&#34; title=&#34;Thank you sir&#34; &gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>